<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<response><creator>APITUBE (https://apitube.pub)</creator><total_count>10</total_count><updated_at>2022-11-03T07:03:54+00:00</updated_at><items><item><title>Nintendo delays Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2 to spring 2023</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/nintendo-delays-zelda-breath-of-the-wild-2-to-spring-2023/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T07:03:11+00:00</created_at><description>It got one of those fateful Metroid Prime 4 videos Although Nintendo is rather secretive about a lot of things, they are pretty open about release dates and delays. And with that in mind, Zelda: Breath of the...</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It got one of those fateful &lt;em&gt;Metroid Prime 4&lt;/em&gt; videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Nintendo is rather secretive about a lot of things, they are pretty open about release dates and delays. And with that in mind, &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/breath-of-the-wild-2-gameplay-2022-window/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has become a 2023 game. Most of us knew that 2022 was too good to be true! More like &lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2&lt;/em&gt; 2023!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the full statement from series producer Eiji Aonuma, &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_vgseuw_o8"&gt;straight from Nintendo’s YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We previously announced that we were aiming for a 2022 release for this game. However, we have decided to extend our development time a bit and change the release to spring 2023.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that’s the first 30 seconds of the video. The following minute consists of showing off footage of the sequel that Nintendo gave us last year at E3, with Aonuma issuing an apology for the delay, and talking up the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;section&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="@destructoid" href="https://www.tiktok.com/@destructoid"&gt;@destructoid&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Will cherish every moment leading up to BOTW 2, and once it’s actually here. &lt;a title="fyp" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/fyp"&gt;#fyp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="foryoupage" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/foryoupage"&gt;#foryoupage&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="breathofthewild" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/breathofthewild"&gt;#breathofthewild&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="botw" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/botw"&gt;#botw&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="zelda" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/zelda"&gt;#zelda&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a title="legendofzelda" target="_blank" href="https://www.tiktok.com/tag/legendofzelda"&gt;#legendofzelda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" title="♬ Hello Gentle Breeze - Official Sound Studio" href="https://www.tiktok.com/music/Hello-Gentle-Breeze-6937924984262117378"&gt;♬ Hello Gentle Breeze – Official Sound Studio&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes all the sense in the world. There is so much pressure for this game to deliver, and the original &lt;em&gt;Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; is still widely talked about and beloved today. I mean, I wouldn’t even count out a further delay beyond spring 2023, because even that seems early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry if I cursed everyone! Let’s check back in a year to see what happens. In the meantime I hope we get a title announcement at E3 this year along with some new gameplay to chew on. Remember the days when you’d download 360p videos of upcoming big games and study them for hours? Maybe? Well I’m definitely doing it with &lt;em&gt;Breath of the Wild 2&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2&lt;/em&gt; 2023 delay announcement:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/f_vgseuw_o8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
It got one of those fateful Metroid Prime 4 videos
Although Nintendo is rather secretive about a lot of things, they are pretty open about release dates and delays. And with that in mind, Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2 has become a 2023 game. Most of us knew that 2022 was too good to be true! More like Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2 2023!
Here’s the full statement from series producer Eiji Aonuma, straight from Nintendo’s YouTube channel:
“We previously announced that we were aiming for a 2022 release for this game. However, we have decided to extend our development time a bit and change the release to spring 2023.”
So that’s the first 30 seconds of the video. The following minute consists of showing off footage of the sequel that Nintendo gave us last year at E3, with Aonuma issuing an apology for the delay, and talking up the game.

 @destructoid 
Will cherish every moment leading up to BOTW 2, and once it’s actually here. #fyp #foryoupage #breathofthewild #botw #zelda #legendofzelda
 ♬ Hello Gentle Breeze – Official Sound Studio 

It makes all the sense in the world. There is so much pressure for this game to deliver, and the original Breath of the Wild is still widely talked about and beloved today. I mean, I wouldn’t even count out a further delay beyond spring 2023, because even that seems early.
Sorry if I cursed everyone! Let’s check back in a year to see what happens. In the meantime I hope we get a title announcement at E3 this year along with some new gameplay to chew on. Remember the days when you’d download 360p videos of upcoming big games and study them for hours? Maybe? Well I’m definitely doing it with Breath of the Wild 2.
Zelda: Breath of the Wild 2 2023 delay announcement:


 

Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!



</textplain><image>https://d23gn3985hkc32.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/03/Zelda-Breath-of-the-Wild-2-2023.jpg</image></item><item><title>Nintendo Download: NBA 2K23</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/nintendo-download-nba-2k23/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T07:03:54+00:00</created_at><description>Also, Return to Monkey Island Not a whole lot is out on the eShop this week, coming off of the release of Splatoon 3. As announced in a recent Nintendo Direct presentation, Various Daylife is out now: but it...</description><content>&lt;article&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/NBA.jpg" alt="Nintendo Download: NBA 2K23" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Also, &lt;em&gt;Return to Monkey Island&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not a whole lot is out on the eShop this week, coming off of the release of &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-splatoon-3-switch/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Splatoon 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. As announced in &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/recap-everything-that-happened-at-the-packed-september-2022-nintendo-direct/"&gt;a recent Nintendo Direct presentation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Various Daylife&lt;/em&gt; is out now: but it actually came out two days ago directly following the stream. &lt;em&gt;NBA 2K23&lt;/em&gt; is also out today on Switch, as is &lt;em&gt;Bear &amp;amp; Breakfast&lt;/em&gt;. You may recall for the latter that the Switch version was delayed last-minute, but it seems everything is sorted now. &lt;em&gt;Return to Monkey Island&lt;/em&gt; rounds out the week, but it doesn’t arrive until September 19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming up next for Nintendo in terms of big releases: &lt;em&gt;Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope&lt;/em&gt; (October 20) and &lt;em&gt;Bayonetta 3 &lt;/em&gt;(October 28), in late-October-ish. We can likely expect the following weeks to pick up when it comes to raw eShop game output, with enough room from &lt;em&gt;Splatoon 3&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Absolute Tactics: Daughters of Mercy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accident&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amnesia: Later x Crowd&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Amnesia: Memories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ankora: Lost Days&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arcade Archives CHAMPION WRESTLER&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brutal Chase Turbo&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Devoured by Darkness&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dungeons 3 – Nintendo Switch Edition&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Family Man&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foretales&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gold Crusader&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gunslingers &amp;amp; Zombies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innocence Island&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jack Move&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Japanese Escape Games The Mansion of Tricks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kitten’s Head Football&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last Beat Enhanced&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mozart Requiem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Paddles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;PBA Pro Bowling 2023&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Plunder Panic&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poly Link – Origins&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Queen’s Garden – Sakura Season&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reknum DX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sacred Valley&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;SAOMI&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silent Sector&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Soulsland&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dark Prophecy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unichrome: A 1-Bit Unicorn Adventure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wayward Strand&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Windmill Engine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you missed last week’s edition, &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/tag/dsi/" target="_blank"&gt;here it is&lt;/a&gt;. For those who are interested, &lt;a href="https://www.nintendo.com/store/sales-and-deals/" target="_blank"&gt;sales are going on&lt;/a&gt; for all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><textplain>
 

Also, Return to Monkey Island
Not a whole lot is out on the eShop this week, coming off of the release of Splatoon 3. As announced in a recent Nintendo Direct presentation, Various Daylife is out now: but it actually came out two days ago directly following the stream. NBA 2K23 is also out today on Switch, as is Bear &amp;amp; Breakfast. You may recall for the latter that the Switch version was delayed last-minute, but it seems everything is sorted now. Return to Monkey Island rounds out the week, but it doesn’t arrive until September 19.
Coming up next for Nintendo in terms of big releases: Mario + Rabbids Sparks of Hope (October 20) and Bayonetta 3 (October 28), in late-October-ish. We can likely expect the following weeks to pick up when it comes to raw eShop game output, with enough room from Splatoon 3.

Absolute Tactics: Daughters of Mercy
Accident
Amnesia: Later x Crowd
Amnesia: Memories
Ankora: Lost Days
Arcade Archives CHAMPION WRESTLER
Brutal Chase Turbo
Devoured by Darkness
Dungeons 3 – Nintendo Switch Edition
Family Man
Foretales
Gold Crusader
Gunslingers &amp;amp; Zombies
Innocence Island
Jack Move
Japanese Escape Games The Mansion of Tricks
Kitten’s Head Football
Last Beat Enhanced
Mozart Requiem
Paddles
PBA Pro Bowling 2023
Plunder Panic
Poly Link – Origins
Queen’s Garden – Sakura Season
Reknum DX
Sacred Valley
SAOMI
Silent Sector
Soulsland
The Dark Prophecy
Unichrome: A 1-Bit Unicorn Adventure
Wayward Strand
Windmill Engine

If you missed last week’s edition, here it is. For those who are interested, sales are going on for all platforms.

 

Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!




</textplain><image>https://d23gn3985hkc32.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/NBA.jpg</image></item><item><title>The first few hours of Tales of Arise are all about its dual protagonists</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/tales-of-arise-preview-first-few-hours/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T07:02:50+00:00</created_at><description>The newest Tales finds its core with its Odd Couple pair of heroes Having good leads in an RPG can be make-or-break for some games. Any lengthy role-playing game will likely ask you to spend somewhere from 40...</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The newest Tales finds its core with its &lt;em&gt;Odd Couple &lt;/em&gt;pair of heroes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having good leads in an RPG can be make-or-break for some games. Any lengthy role-playing game will likely ask you to spend somewhere from 40 or more hours with its cast, and the majority of it with the protagonist. That time gets easier if the protagonist is likeable, and thankfully, I really liked both of the protagonists of &lt;em&gt;Tales of Arise&lt;/em&gt; during its first few hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tales games, at least those I’ve played, have had some pretty good leads. I’d put Velvet Crowe and Yuri Lowell up as some of my favorites, and while I’m not sure if Alphen or Shionne are hitting those highs yet, I’ve enjoyed the time I’ve spent with them thus far. We had a chance to play through the first “section” of &lt;i&gt;Tales of Arise&lt;/i&gt;, roughly the first few hours which introduce you to both characters; Alphen, the amnesiac man in the iron mask, and Shionne, the runaway royalty with her fair share of secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For context, the world of &lt;em&gt;Tales of Arise&lt;/em&gt; has two distinct nations: Dahna and Rena. Hundreds of years before the start of Arise, Rena invaded Dahna and subjugated its people, resulting in a present-day scenario of technologically advanced, militarily superior Rena forcing the Dahnan populace into servitude. Dahnan civilians are also unable to use astral artes, like healing, and are often outfitted with special crystals by the Renans. Those seem significant, though it’s not clear just how yet, outside them acting as a symbol of Renan power over the Dahnans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TalesofArise_CityBeams_061721.jpg?resize=640%2C360" alt /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, the protagonists end up meeting by chance: Alphen, who’s been working in the Dahnan labor camps for about a year with no memory prior, winds up running into Shionne as she’s escaping both Dahnan resistance fighters and Renan soldiers. As events progress, it becomes clear each has their own reason for wanting to fight against the Renan occupation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alphen has been, quite literally, thrust into a Man In The Iron Mask situation, working away his days with no face, name, or memories. In fact, for most of the intro, he just goes by Iron Mask. Day in and day out, he sees the cruelties inflicted on the Dahnan population, as they struggle and die laboring under Renan command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shionne, meanwhile, is a tad more mysterious. I got the sense there are greater motivations we have yet to learn, outside of the section I got to play, but the short version we’re presented with is that she’s being hunted by the Renans. She’s quickly positioned as both Renan and unlike the others, where she still has misgivings about working with the Dahnans. An entire plot point is about getting Shionne some Renan armor to wear, rather than Dahnan attire. But she also seems to greatly dislike the ruling class of Rena; she stole something precious from the local Renan lord, and with it, she’s attempting to overthrow the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a very enemy-of-my-enemy setup, and the two protagonists often bicker and snipe at each other. Alphen is blissfully headstrong and sure of himself, even when it could lead to his own demise, while Shionne is cautious and reserved when it comes to discussing anything about herself. It becomes clear over time that both are trying to expand their view of the dual worlds they live in, while also fighting their internalized beliefs about each other’s worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This thematically ties into their own abilities as well. Shionne can use astral artes, most notably healing, but also carries within her a flaming sword. Normally, the sword would scald anyone who wields it, and Shionne herself emits lightning (colloquially referred to as “thorns”) when anyone attempts to get near or touch her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it so happens, Alphen cannot feel pain, which is normally a bad thing, as he comments that he could be near death and not realize it at times. But when it comes to wielding a flaming sword, or working with a woman who shocks those around her, it comes in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/06/TalesofArise_Shionne_061721.jpg?resize=640%2C360" alt /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So these two, who stumbled into each other due to coincidence and find themselves working together due to an unlikely combination of complementary talents, are begrudgingly forced together. And watching them go through ebbs and flows of opening up and closing themselves off, wrestling with their own preconceptions and the secrets each is hiding, drives much of the early game of &lt;em&gt;Tales of Arise&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early section we saw only featured these characters, unlike our previous preview which &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/tales-of-arise-preview-e3-2021/" target="_blank"&gt;let us go hands-on with a party of six fighters&lt;/a&gt;. Most of my comments on the battles, world exploration, and other systems hold true in the early hours. Using Boost Attacks and Boost Strikes emphasized the party aspect of combat, and with only two people to work with, much of the early game felt like Alphen and Shionne growing accustomed to working in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got to see some skits, a staple of the Tales series. For those who haven’t played a Tales game before &lt;em&gt;Tales of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arise&lt;/em&gt; or need a refresher, these are short side scenes that play as you travel around the map or through a dungeon. They’re largely optional, and simply pop up as an option in the bottom-right corner; hit the button, and you’re treated to a minute or two of the characters talking amongst themselves about anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can range from moments that build upon individual characters, to exploring party dynamics, and even to silly one-off goofs and jokes. In past Tales games, they’ve also frequently let characters speak their minds on what’s been going on in the main story, or highlighted certain dynamics and how they can create their own tensions and moments of growth for the group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re legitimately one of my favorite parts of the Tales series, something that contributes to the series’ overall feel to me as a game about your party, and seeing them interact with and change each other over the course of the journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bNpekwPPP50?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At just a few hours, it was a little early in &lt;em&gt;Tales of Arise&lt;/em&gt; to get a sense of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bNpekwPPP50" target="_blank"&gt;breadth of skits&lt;/a&gt; (and I also didn’t really have the party size to explore that in the first place), but I will say one noticeable change is the production value of them. Rather than talking heads, comic panels with characters posing and occasionally animating move in and out. It’s not a drastic change, as they’re not really “cutscenes” or anything, but it’s a noticeable change that I hope can allow for skits to cover more ground and show more interactions, like two characters sparring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the first few hours of &lt;em&gt;Tales of Arise&lt;/em&gt; have me invested. It’s a good start, with some neat change-ups to the formula that have been gone over already. But storywise, I really want to see where Alphen and Shionne end up going with their arcs, both individually and as a pair. Whether their dynamic can keep things interesting throughout the length of a full-scale RPG is one thing, but in the short glimpse I got to see of it, I’m already pretty endeared to this prickly pairing of protagonists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
The newest Tales finds its core with its Odd Couple pair of heroes
Having good leads in an RPG can be make-or-break for some games. Any lengthy role-playing game will likely ask you to spend somewhere from 40 or more hours with its cast, and the majority of it with the protagonist. That time gets easier if the protagonist is likeable, and thankfully, I really liked both of the protagonists of Tales of Arise during its first few hours.
Tales games, at least those I’ve played, have had some pretty good leads. I’d put Velvet Crowe and Yuri Lowell up as some of my favorites, and while I’m not sure if Alphen or Shionne are hitting those highs yet, I’ve enjoyed the time I’ve spent with them thus far. We had a chance to play through the first “section” of Tales of Arise, roughly the first few hours which introduce you to both characters; Alphen, the amnesiac man in the iron mask, and Shionne, the runaway royalty with her fair share of secrets.
For context, the world of Tales of Arise has two distinct nations: Dahna and Rena. Hundreds of years before the start of Arise, Rena invaded Dahna and subjugated its people, resulting in a present-day scenario of technologically advanced, militarily superior Rena forcing the Dahnan populace into servitude. Dahnan civilians are also unable to use astral artes, like healing, and are often outfitted with special crystals by the Renans. Those seem significant, though it’s not clear just how yet, outside them acting as a symbol of Renan power over the Dahnans.

Initially, the protagonists end up meeting by chance: Alphen, who’s been working in the Dahnan labor camps for about a year with no memory prior, winds up running into Shionne as she’s escaping both Dahnan resistance fighters and Renan soldiers. As events progress, it becomes clear each has their own reason for wanting to fight against the Renan occupation.
Alphen has been, quite literally, thrust into a Man In The Iron Mask situation, working away his days with no face, name, or memories. In fact, for most of the intro, he just goes by Iron Mask. Day in and day out, he sees the cruelties inflicted on the Dahnan population, as they struggle and die laboring under Renan command.
Shionne, meanwhile, is a tad more mysterious. I got the sense there are greater motivations we have yet to learn, outside of the section I got to play, but the short version we’re presented with is that she’s being hunted by the Renans. She’s quickly positioned as both Renan and unlike the others, where she still has misgivings about working with the Dahnans. An entire plot point is about getting Shionne some Renan armor to wear, rather than Dahnan attire. But she also seems to greatly dislike the ruling class of Rena; she stole something precious from the local Renan lord, and with it, she’s attempting to overthrow the whole system.
It’s a very enemy-of-my-enemy setup, and the two protagonists often bicker and snipe at each other. Alphen is blissfully headstrong and sure of himself, even when it could lead to his own demise, while Shionne is cautious and reserved when it comes to discussing anything about herself. It becomes clear over time that both are trying to expand their view of the dual worlds they live in, while also fighting their internalized beliefs about each other’s worlds.
This thematically ties into their own abilities as well. Shionne can use astral artes, most notably healing, but also carries within her a flaming sword. Normally, the sword would scald anyone who wields it, and Shionne herself emits lightning (colloquially referred to as “thorns”) when anyone attempts to get near or touch her.
As it so happens, Alphen cannot feel pain, which is normally a bad thing, as he comments that he could be near death and not realize it at times. But when it comes to wielding a flaming sword, or working with a woman who shocks those around her, it comes in handy.

So these two, who stumbled into each other due to coincidence and find themselves working together due to an unlikely combination of complementary talents, are begrudgingly forced together. And watching them go through ebbs and flows of opening up and closing themselves off, wrestling with their own preconceptions and the secrets each is hiding, drives much of the early game of Tales of Arise.
The early section we saw only featured these characters, unlike our previous preview which let us go hands-on with a party of six fighters. Most of my comments on the battles, world exploration, and other systems hold true in the early hours. Using Boost Attacks and Boost Strikes emphasized the party aspect of combat, and with only two people to work with, much of the early game felt like Alphen and Shionne growing accustomed to working in tandem.
I also got to see some skits, a staple of the Tales series. For those who haven’t played a Tales game before Tales of Arise or need a refresher, these are short side scenes that play as you travel around the map or through a dungeon. They’re largely optional, and simply pop up as an option in the bottom-right corner; hit the button, and you’re treated to a minute or two of the characters talking amongst themselves about anything.
These can range from moments that build upon individual characters, to exploring party dynamics, and even to silly one-off goofs and jokes. In past Tales games, they’ve also frequently let characters speak their minds on what’s been going on in the main story, or highlighted certain dynamics and how they can create their own tensions and moments of growth for the group.
They’re legitimately one of my favorite parts of the Tales series, something that contributes to the series’ overall feel to me as a game about your party, and seeing them interact with and change each other over the course of the journey.

At just a few hours, it was a little early in Tales of Arise to get a sense of the breadth of skits (and I also didn’t really have the party size to explore that in the first place), but I will say one noticeable change is the production value of them. Rather than talking heads, comic panels with characters posing and occasionally animating move in and out. It’s not a drastic change, as they’re not really “cutscenes” or anything, but it’s a noticeable change that I hope can allow for skits to cover more ground and show more interactions, like two characters sparring.
Overall, the first few hours of Tales of Arise have me invested. It’s a good start, with some neat change-ups to the formula that have been gone over already. But storywise, I really want to see where Alphen and Shionne end up going with their arcs, both individually and as a pair. Whether their dynamic can keep things interesting throughout the length of a full-scale RPG is one thing, but in the short glimpse I got to see of it, I’m already pretty endeared to this prickly pairing of protagonists.
</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/08/TalesOfArise_ArtLead_081021.jpg</image></item><item><title>Overwatch 2 hits 25 million player milestone in 10 days</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/overwatch-2-25-million-player-milestone-launch-blizzard-multiplayer/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T07:02:44+00:00</created_at><description>And only 46 were on the payload It appears that, right off of the bat, Blizzard Entertainment’s decision to go free-to-play with its hero shooter sequel Overwatch 2 has the required effect — The studio has...</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And only 46 were on the payload&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that, right off of the bat, Blizzard Entertainment’s decision to go free-to-play with its hero shooter sequel &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/early-access-review-overwatch-2-pc/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has the required effect — &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/PlayOverwatch/status/761317633979539456?s=20&amp;amp;t=56xJEj1y6_F9MuY0Cf9O7w" target="_blank"&gt;The studio has announced&lt;/a&gt; that the charismatic multiplayer title has already rocketed past 25 million players in its first 10 days of release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number far supersedes that of the original 2016 premium title, which hit around 15 million players during its early launch months.  Blizzard has also noted that daily player counts are already tripling those of the original &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt; by almost 300%, though what percentage of these players are Reaper mains was not offered up at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/LGgqyer-qr4?feature=oembed&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The launch of&lt;em&gt; Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; has been such an important moment for Blizzard,” said Blizzard president Mike Ybarra.  “This is only the beginning — there are so many possibilities to explore in the world of &lt;em&gt;Overwatch&lt;/em&gt;, and we cannot wait for players to experience everything the team is building for the live game.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ybarra is likely referencing the upcoming PvE content, which was expected to form a core element of &lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; and yet is curiously missing &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; from the launch edition.  It is believed that this content — including a “campaign” scenario and single-player missions — will arrive at some point in late 2023.  This will no doubt cause another spike in player numbers even if the sequel’s popularity settles down over the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-time Overwatcher, I have unfortunately not had the time to really delve into &lt;em&gt;OW2&lt;/em&gt; as of yet, but I did find it to be a finely polished and great-looking remix of the original release — especially the console editions.  Whether &lt;em&gt;OW2&lt;/em&gt; can be called a true “sequel”, in the commonly accepted use of the phrase, is still up for debate.  Regardless, the brand is still clearly hot for the time being, as depicted by these numbers.  Whether such popularity remains once the launch hype dies down remains to be seen, and will be the true testament to the sequel’s staying power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overwatch 2&lt;/em&gt; is available now on PlayStation, PC, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch platforms.  You can read an abridged timeline of California’s lawsuit against Activision Blizzard lawsuit, as well as the numerous accusations of toxicity leveled against the studio, &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/activision-blizzard-lawsuit-timeline-industry-ceo-bobby-kotick-report/" target="_blank"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/av-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/av-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Senior Editor - Chris has been playing video games since the 1980s. Former Saturday Night Slam Master. Graduated from Galaxy High with honors. Twitter: @ChrisxMoyse&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
And only 46 were on the payload
It appears that, right off of the bat, Blizzard Entertainment’s decision to go free-to-play with its hero shooter sequel Overwatch 2 has the required effect — The studio has announced that the charismatic multiplayer title has already rocketed past 25 million players in its first 10 days of release.
The number far supersedes that of the original 2016 premium title, which hit around 15 million players during its early launch months.  Blizzard has also noted that daily player counts are already tripling those of the original Overwatch by almost 300%, though what percentage of these players are Reaper mains was not offered up at this time.

“The launch of Overwatch 2 has been such an important moment for Blizzard,” said Blizzard president Mike Ybarra.  “This is only the beginning — there are so many possibilities to explore in the world of Overwatch, and we cannot wait for players to experience everything the team is building for the live game.”
Ybarra is likely referencing the upcoming PvE content, which was expected to form a core element of Overwatch 2 and yet is curiously missing entirely from the launch edition.  It is believed that this content — including a “campaign” scenario and single-player missions — will arrive at some point in late 2023.  This will no doubt cause another spike in player numbers even if the sequel’s popularity settles down over the coming months.
As a long-time Overwatcher, I have unfortunately not had the time to really delve into OW2 as of yet, but I did find it to be a finely polished and great-looking remix of the original release — especially the console editions.  Whether OW2 can be called a true “sequel”, in the commonly accepted use of the phrase, is still up for debate.  Regardless, the brand is still clearly hot for the time being, as depicted by these numbers.  Whether such popularity remains once the launch hype dies down remains to be seen, and will be the true testament to the sequel’s staying power.
Overwatch 2 is available now on PlayStation, PC, Xbox, and Nintendo Switch platforms.  You can read an abridged timeline of California’s lawsuit against Activision Blizzard lawsuit, as well as the numerous accusations of toxicity leveled against the studio, right here.

 

Senior Editor - Chris has been playing video games since the 1980s. Former Saturday Night Slam Master. Graduated from Galaxy High with honors. Twitter: @ChrisxMoyse



</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/overwatch-2-junker-queen-launch-numbers.jpg</image></item><item><title>Blaseball is back, and ready to warp splorts reality once again</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/blaseball-returns-interview-the-game-band-mobile-sports-new-era/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T04:55:02+00:00</created_at><description>We talk to the Blaseball team about what’s in store for the new Era It was the year 2020, and everyone was inside. The world was slowly coming to grips with a pandemic, and everyone was indoors and online....</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We talk to the &lt;em&gt;Blaseball &lt;/em&gt;team about what’s in store for the new Era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was the year 2020, and everyone was inside. The world was slowly coming to grips with a pandemic, and everyone was indoors and online. Amid it all, there was &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;is, at its most distilled form, a sports game. Users join through the website and assign themselves to a team of choice, like the Houston Spies or Baltimore Crabs, either through regional loyalty or just digging their vibe. Each team is populated by generated players, who play out their games in A.I.-driven baseball games, like watching a bunch of CPU opponents fight in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Super Smash Bros.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The teams play matches throughout the week, effectively simulating a season of baseball, and users bet in-game currency on the outcomes, akin to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/saltybet-lets-you-bet-zenny-on-spawn-vs-garfield-fights/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Salty Bet matches&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. Those earnings can be used for your own purposes, or to help the team try and secure certain advantages through a bidding process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y5t8DwnDE1k?feature=oembed&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And this is where &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;gave way to its, let’s say, stranger side. Because the “splort” itself is just a piece of the greater puzzle. What &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;truly became was a greater work of community and collaborative fiction. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Developer The Game Band would incorporate bizarre rules and situations, like extra bases for one team to run or blooddrain raining down on the field. Star players would be incinerated in matches. A peanut god entombed competitors in peanut shells. Wild times.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A new Era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So it’s 2022, and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;is back. The Game Band is kicking off a season of Fall Ball as a build-up to the new Era. After a Great Siesta and a lot of time poking, prodding, and examining, the team is reapproaching what &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I sat down with Sam Rosenthal, Joel Clark, and Stephen Bell, three leads behind &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;and its upcoming return. And as Rosenthal describes it, the team has taken a chance to look at what they want &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;to be at a higher level. The first version was very “reactive,” Rosenthal says, and went well beyond expectations. But the cadence, methods, and team size were not sustainable.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Game Band now stands at 27 employees strong, up from the “five or six” they started &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;with. And a new version of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;is powering it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“It’s kind of like a rethinking, a reboot, of what &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;was,” said Rosenthal.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BLASEBALL PLAYERS FALLING FROM THE SKY???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FALL BALL is LIVE: The Black Hole is burping players back out in a random draft. &lt;br /&gt;Who makes a return? Which team will they land on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up to stay tuned, unlock Rewards to slowly reveal our brand new universe!&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/yzFhFKgWPu"&gt;https://t.co/yzFhFKgWPu&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/gqZgBuhfXV"&gt;pic.twitter.com/gqZgBuhfXV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— The Game Band (@thegameband) &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/thegameband/status/1585318318545637376?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 26, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Fall Ball&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Approachability and community are two aspects Rosenthal goes on to highlight as changes. A core focal point of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;has been its community; teams’ fans assemble in Discords and on social media, organizing planning sessions alongside charity efforts and general outreach. The robust community aspects made &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;feel heaven-sent amid the pandemic. But it’s also made it tough for newcomers arriving, and seeing floods of messages, in-language, and constant games, to know where to start.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Fall Ball is helping with that. The current event is described by The Game band as a prologue event, showing a universe in formation. Players are, for lack of a better term, being “burped” into the universe and dropped onto random teams. There’s some anticipation on who will appear in this world. And also, it provides a nice onboarding point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Still, the core of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;is its emergent narrative. No other anecdote is as effective as illustrating this than the story of Jaylen Hotdogfingers. The pitcher was effectively raised from the dead through a bit of a loophole, and then became a necromantic terror that was beaning batters at the plate to mark them for incineration. Jaylen and so many others became tall tales, living legends of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;scene that drove the drama between each A.I.-driven sim session.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/diAHuUV2Meg?feature=oembed&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Emerging narrative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Game Band calls &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;an emergent narrative game. “That’s not going away,” Clark tells me. And while there is improvisation, the studio has also been able to map out a bit more in advance thanks to the break time between the conclusion of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;’s Discipline Era and now.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“We do still plan to be improvisational, and like, be able to build on these fan stories during this Era, but so much of it’s planned in advance,” said Clark. “So we have to find this balance of designing the possibility space where fans might take the emergent narrative. When we’re designing each season, we see where it might go, where were the corners that the fans might find and take this in?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Game Band previously had to work around edge cases like Jaylen’s necromancy on the fly, as Bell tells me. The team was always planning ahead before. But the big change has been having so much time to map out a whole possibility space.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“We, previously, had a small possibility space, and then we would be rushing to expand it over the course of an Era,” said Rosenthal. “And now we have taken the time to really think through what we want the possibility space to be, and have a better sense for where we can jump in and react, you know, based on what the fans latch onto.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Talk to me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The communication aspect is also one The Game Band has considered. The team didn’t go into too much detail on exactly what it’s planning. But it is thinking about aspects of how people organize and participate outside of the game, and to be more intentional with how the community can talk to one another.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Discords are still going to have a place in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;, the team assures. But they’re not networks the team made, and they’ve become core parts of the experience. The team has been thinking a lot about what worked well and didn’t work well with those aspects, as it looks at ways to help people connect in the game.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Core parts of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;will continue to remain, though. The sparseness, Clark says, goes a long way towards the game being improvisational. It’s easier to be more mysterious and adaptive when a game doesn’t need massive 3D models, after all. But &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;is getting “a fresh coat of paint,” to add a bit more to the experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;More points the team examined include making big moments clearer, so users have a better idea of when to “tune in” for something big. Season will feel very different as the games roll on, too. The sim is fairly new, if not totally new. That means changing some aspects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;“And I’ll stay a little vague here, but it’s really giving us more ground to cover,” said Clark. “And there’s just a lot more that we can play with there.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bell mentions worrying about how many more ways the team could have played with baseball. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;has had catastrophic weather and incinerations. It turned a contest with a peanut god into a live RPG boss battle. Bell even jokes about an idea he pitched, exponential runs, that never saw the light of day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HEADS UP&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/Mc6AD3NyEm"&gt;https://t.co/Mc6AD3NyEm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— BLASEBALL COMMISSIONER HAUNTED (@blaseball) &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/blaseball/status/1585316187944022017?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;October 26, 2022&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Expanding the game&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;When looking at how to expand and add depth, Bell cites &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dwarf Fortress&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The idea of expanding interiority, in the case of the dwarves, can add more of that depth. The team is being understandably vague, as the mystery and deeper lore is a core part of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;that The Game Band is still working to retain, even as it makes the on-ramp easier.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;But with the new Era of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;, it doesn’t feel like The Game Band is trying to recapture the moment. It’s not really possible to do that anyways. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;, as it was in 2020, was of its time. And now the team is looking at what &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;can be in 2022. It’s daunting, but as a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;aficionado, pretty exciting.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Through a mobile app, on-boarding and helping players who only jump on for five minutes a time, the doors to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Blaseball &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;doors are opening a bit more. It’s this bizarre, otherworld “splort” that is happening in the background. Until a notification hits your phone, and chaos lets loose. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This is the start of a new universe, picking up where the old one left off. The Game Band seems intent on bringing in old &lt;em&gt;Blaseball &lt;/em&gt;fans and newcomers alike.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;And as Clark jokes at the conclusion of our chat: “We’re hoping it’s just as cursed.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
We talk to the Blaseball team about what’s in store for the new Era
It was the year 2020, and everyone was inside. The world was slowly coming to grips with a pandemic, and everyone was indoors and online. Amid it all, there was Blaseball.
Blaseball is, at its most distilled form, a sports game. Users join through the website and assign themselves to a team of choice, like the Houston Spies or Baltimore Crabs, either through regional loyalty or just digging their vibe. Each team is populated by generated players, who play out their games in A.I.-driven baseball games, like watching a bunch of CPU opponents fight in Super Smash Bros.
The teams play matches throughout the week, effectively simulating a season of baseball, and users bet in-game currency on the outcomes, akin to Salty Bet matches. Those earnings can be used for your own purposes, or to help the team try and secure certain advantages through a bidding process.

And this is where Blaseball gave way to its, let’s say, stranger side. Because the “splort” itself is just a piece of the greater puzzle. What Blaseball truly became was a greater work of community and collaborative fiction. 
Developer The Game Band would incorporate bizarre rules and situations, like extra bases for one team to run or blooddrain raining down on the field. Star players would be incinerated in matches. A peanut god entombed competitors in peanut shells. Wild times.
A new Era
So it’s 2022, and Blaseball is back. The Game Band is kicking off a season of Fall Ball as a build-up to the new Era. After a Great Siesta and a lot of time poking, prodding, and examining, the team is reapproaching what Blaseball is.
I sat down with Sam Rosenthal, Joel Clark, and Stephen Bell, three leads behind Blaseball and its upcoming return. And as Rosenthal describes it, the team has taken a chance to look at what they want Blaseball to be at a higher level. The first version was very “reactive,” Rosenthal says, and went well beyond expectations. But the cadence, methods, and team size were not sustainable.
The Game Band now stands at 27 employees strong, up from the “five or six” they started Blaseball with. And a new version of Blaseball is powering it.
“It’s kind of like a rethinking, a reboot, of what Blaseball was,” said Rosenthal.

BLASEBALL PLAYERS FALLING FROM THE SKY???
FALL BALL is LIVE: The Black Hole is burping players back out in a random draft. Who makes a return? Which team will they land on?
Sign up to stay tuned, unlock Rewards to slowly reveal our brand new universe!https://t.co/yzFhFKgWPu pic.twitter.com/gqZgBuhfXV
— The Game Band (@thegameband) October 26, 2022
The Fall Ball
Approachability and community are two aspects Rosenthal goes on to highlight as changes. A core focal point of Blaseball has been its community; teams’ fans assemble in Discords and on social media, organizing planning sessions alongside charity efforts and general outreach. The robust community aspects made Blaseball feel heaven-sent amid the pandemic. But it’s also made it tough for newcomers arriving, and seeing floods of messages, in-language, and constant games, to know where to start.
Fall Ball is helping with that. The current event is described by The Game band as a prologue event, showing a universe in formation. Players are, for lack of a better term, being “burped” into the universe and dropped onto random teams. There’s some anticipation on who will appear in this world. And also, it provides a nice onboarding point.
Still, the core of Blaseball is its emergent narrative. No other anecdote is as effective as illustrating this than the story of Jaylen Hotdogfingers. The pitcher was effectively raised from the dead through a bit of a loophole, and then became a necromantic terror that was beaning batters at the plate to mark them for incineration. Jaylen and so many others became tall tales, living legends of the Blaseball scene that drove the drama between each A.I.-driven sim session.

Emerging narrative
The Game Band calls Blaseball an emergent narrative game. “That’s not going away,” Clark tells me. And while there is improvisation, the studio has also been able to map out a bit more in advance thanks to the break time between the conclusion of Blaseball’s Discipline Era and now.
“We do still plan to be improvisational, and like, be able to build on these fan stories during this Era, but so much of it’s planned in advance,” said Clark. “So we have to find this balance of designing the possibility space where fans might take the emergent narrative. When we’re designing each season, we see where it might go, where were the corners that the fans might find and take this in?”
The Game Band previously had to work around edge cases like Jaylen’s necromancy on the fly, as Bell tells me. The team was always planning ahead before. But the big change has been having so much time to map out a whole possibility space.
“We, previously, had a small possibility space, and then we would be rushing to expand it over the course of an Era,” said Rosenthal. “And now we have taken the time to really think through what we want the possibility space to be, and have a better sense for where we can jump in and react, you know, based on what the fans latch onto.”
Talk to me
The communication aspect is also one The Game Band has considered. The team didn’t go into too much detail on exactly what it’s planning. But it is thinking about aspects of how people organize and participate outside of the game, and to be more intentional with how the community can talk to one another.
Discords are still going to have a place in Blaseball, the team assures. But they’re not networks the team made, and they’ve become core parts of the experience. The team has been thinking a lot about what worked well and didn’t work well with those aspects, as it looks at ways to help people connect in the game.
Core parts of Blaseball will continue to remain, though. The sparseness, Clark says, goes a long way towards the game being improvisational. It’s easier to be more mysterious and adaptive when a game doesn’t need massive 3D models, after all. But Blaseball is getting “a fresh coat of paint,” to add a bit more to the experience.
More points the team examined include making big moments clearer, so users have a better idea of when to “tune in” for something big. Season will feel very different as the games roll on, too. The sim is fairly new, if not totally new. That means changing some aspects.
“And I’ll stay a little vague here, but it’s really giving us more ground to cover,” said Clark. “And there’s just a lot more that we can play with there.”
Bell mentions worrying about how many more ways the team could have played with baseball. Blaseball has had catastrophic weather and incinerations. It turned a contest with a peanut god into a live RPG boss battle. Bell even jokes about an idea he pitched, exponential runs, that never saw the light of day.

HEADS UPhttps://t.co/Mc6AD3NyEm
— BLASEBALL COMMISSIONER HAUNTED (@blaseball) October 26, 2022
Expanding the game
When looking at how to expand and add depth, Bell cites Dwarf Fortress. The idea of expanding interiority, in the case of the dwarves, can add more of that depth. The team is being understandably vague, as the mystery and deeper lore is a core part of Blaseball that The Game Band is still working to retain, even as it makes the on-ramp easier.
But with the new Era of Blaseball, it doesn’t feel like The Game Band is trying to recapture the moment. It’s not really possible to do that anyways. Blaseball, as it was in 2020, was of its time. And now the team is looking at what Blaseball can be in 2022. It’s daunting, but as a Blaseball aficionado, pretty exciting.
Through a mobile app, on-boarding and helping players who only jump on for five minutes a time, the doors to Blaseball doors are opening a bit more. It’s this bizarre, otherworld “splort” that is happening in the background. Until a notification hits your phone, and chaos lets loose. This is the start of a new universe, picking up where the old one left off. The Game Band seems intent on bringing in old Blaseball fans and newcomers alike.
And as Clark jokes at the conclusion of our chat: “We’re hoping it’s just as cursed.”
</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Blaseball_Return_102722.jpg</image></item><item><title>Sega insists that Sonic Frontiers is still coming in 2022</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/sonic-frontiers-is-it-still-coming-in-2022/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T05:06:47+00:00</created_at><description>News is coming “soon” As we charge further onward into a potential Sonic Frontiers 2022 release, Sega has been mum on any info on the game outside of the single reveal trailer: that may change “soon,” but for...</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Sonic-Frontiers-2022.jpg" alt="Sonic Frontiers 2022" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;News is coming “soon”&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we charge further onward into a potential &lt;em&gt;Sonic Frontiers&lt;/em&gt; 2022 release, Sega has been mum on any info on the game &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/sonic-frontiers-is-an-open-world-sonic-game-coming-in-late-2022/"&gt;outside of the single reveal trailer&lt;/a&gt;: that may change “soon,” but for now, Sega is sticking to the 2022 launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.nintendolife.com/news/2022/04/sega-to-share-sonic-frontiers-news-update-soon"&gt;Spotted by Nintendo Life&lt;/a&gt;, the new &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aPhhou_o_aY"&gt;Sonic Official livestream&lt;/a&gt; that aired recently acknowledged the &lt;em&gt;Sonic Frontiers&lt;/em&gt; situation directly. After noting that news will come “soon,” Katie Chrzanowski (social media manager for Sega) also reconfirmed the “holiday” 2022 release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“[We] see a lot of people asking about &lt;em&gt;Frontiers&lt;/em&gt;, we don’t have news on Frontiers today but don’t worry. It’s still set to come out this holiday, so we will have news for you this year, don’t worry.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Sonic Frontiers&lt;/em&gt; 2022 target could still come to fruition, but we’ve seen statements from company reps evolve over time in the past, especially in this era of supply chain problems that lead to delays. Either way, &lt;strong&gt;it has a lot to live up to, and has a heavy burden on its shoulders following &lt;em&gt;Sonic Forces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that Ian Flynn (of &lt;em&gt;Sonic&lt;/em&gt; comics fame, among many other beloved works) &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/sonic-frontiers-is-an-open-world-sonic-game-coming-in-late-2022/"&gt;is handling the story&lt;/a&gt; is definitely a great sign, as it most assuredly won’t involve excess edge (or torture!) with Flynn involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aPhhou_o_aY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Xbox-Game-Pass-2022-artwork.jpg" alt="Xbox Game Pass family plan" /&gt;			&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;CMA filings show how the Activision Blizzard deal could help build the Xbox mobile store&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid investigations over Microsoft’s &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-purchase-acquisition-call-of-duty-warcraft/" target="_blank"&gt;possible acquisition&lt;/a&gt; of Activision Blizzard, new details have emerged about its plans for a mobile store to compete with other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s Activision Blizzard deal is &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/microsoft-activision-blizzard-deal-under-uk-regulator-investigation-news/" target="_blank"&gt;under investigation&lt;/a&gt; by the UK’s Competition and Markets Authority (CMA). As part of those filings, Microsoft says a motivation for the acquisition is to help build out its mobile presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the relevant item from &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/cma-cases/microsoft-slash-activision-blizzard-merger-inquiry" target="_blank"&gt;the CMA filing&lt;/a&gt;, as reported on by &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2022/10/19/23411972/microsoft-xbox-mobile-store-games" target="_blank"&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The transaction will improve Microsoft’s ability to create a next generation game store which operates across a range of devices, including mobile as a result of the addition of Activision Blizzard’s content. Building on Activision Blizzard’s existing communities of gamers, Xbox will seek to scale the Xbox Store to mobile, attracting gamers to a new Xbox Mobile Platform. Shifting consumers away from the Google Play Store and App Store on mobile devices will, however, require a major shift in consumer behavior. Microsoft hopes that by offering well-known and popular content, gamers will be more inclined to try something new.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RtSmAwpVHsA?feature=oembed&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;origin=https://www.destructoid.com" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A more mobile Xbox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has been pushing more and more into the mobile market. Putting its &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/xbox-cloud-gaming-ios-pc-browser-game-pass-ultimate/" target="_blank"&gt;cloud gaming service&lt;/a&gt; on phones makes for pretty good reasons to pick up a controller clip and game on the go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this new development could see Microsoft opening its own platform, one that would compete with Google’s Play Store and the App Store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mobile gaming revenue from Activision Blizzard is strong, as Microsoft notes in the filing. The output of the King side of Activision Blizzard, alongside games like &lt;em&gt;Call of Duty: Mobile&lt;/em&gt;, represent a good chunk of revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acquisition remains under scrutiny though, as the CMA continues to investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other Activision Blizzard news, Blizzard Albany workers &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/blizzard-albany-union-vote-qa-team-nlrb-activision/" target="_blank"&gt;recently won approval&lt;/a&gt; for a union vote.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DestructoidAvatar_EricVA-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/DestructoidAvatar_EricVA-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt;				&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>


 

News is coming “soon”
As we charge further onward into a potential Sonic Frontiers 2022 release, Sega has been mum on any info on the game outside of the single reveal trailer: that may change “soon,” but for now, Sega is sticking to the 2022 launch.
Spotted by Nintendo Life, the new Sonic Official livestream that aired recently acknowledged the Sonic Frontiers situation directly. After noting that news will come “soon,” Katie Chrzanowski (social media manager for Sega) also reconfirmed the “holiday” 2022 release:
“[We] see a lot of people asking about Frontiers, we don’t have news on Frontiers today but don’t worry. It’s still set to come out this holiday, so we will have news for you this year, don’t worry.”
The Sonic Frontiers 2022 target could still come to fruition, but we’ve seen statements from company reps evolve over time in the past, especially in this era of supply chain problems that lead to delays. Either way, it has a lot to live up to, and has a heavy burden on its shoulders following Sonic Forces.
The fact that Ian Flynn (of Sonic comics fame, among many other beloved works) is handling the story is definitely a great sign, as it most assuredly won’t involve excess edge (or torture!) with Flynn involved.


 

Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!





 


						
	
		CMA filings show how the Activision Blizzard deal could help build the Xbox mobile store
Amid investigations over Microsoft’s possible acquisition of Activision Blizzard, new details have emerged about its plans for a mobile store to compete with other platforms.
Microsoft’s Activision Blizzard deal is under investigation by the UK’s Competition and Markets Authority (CMA). As part of those filings, Microsoft says a motivation for the acquisition is to help build out its mobile presence.
Here’s the relevant item from the CMA filing, as reported on by The Verge:
“The transaction will improve Microsoft’s ability to create a next generation game store which operates across a range of devices, including mobile as a result of the addition of Activision Blizzard’s content. Building on Activision Blizzard’s existing communities of gamers, Xbox will seek to scale the Xbox Store to mobile, attracting gamers to a new Xbox Mobile Platform. Shifting consumers away from the Google Play Store and App Store on mobile devices will, however, require a major shift in consumer behavior. Microsoft hopes that by offering well-known and popular content, gamers will be more inclined to try something new.”

A more mobile Xbox
Microsoft has been pushing more and more into the mobile market. Putting its cloud gaming service on phones makes for pretty good reasons to pick up a controller clip and game on the go.
But this new development could see Microsoft opening its own platform, one that would compete with Google’s Play Store and the App Store.
Mobile gaming revenue from Activision Blizzard is strong, as Microsoft notes in the filing. The output of the King side of Activision Blizzard, alongside games like Call of Duty: Mobile, represent a good chunk of revenue.
The acquisition remains under scrutiny though, as the CMA continues to investigate.
In other Activision Blizzard news, Blizzard Albany workers recently won approval for a union vote.
		
								
			
	

 
</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Sonic-Frontiers-2022.jpg</image></item><item><title>Hades turned me into a hack-and-slash machine</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/hades-turned-me-into-a-hack-and-slash-machine/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T06:28:37+00:00</created_at><description>Ares would be so proud [Narrated by Josh Picard] Hades was love at first sight for me. It has the bright and stylized art that I love, roguelikes are one of my favorite gameplay genres, and I was one of those...</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ares would be so proud&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;sub&gt;[Narrated by Josh Picard]&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; was love at first sight for me. It has the bright and stylized art that I love, roguelikes are one of my favorite gameplay genres, and I was one of those Greek mythology kids who was obsessed with the &lt;em&gt;Percy Jackson&lt;/em&gt; series growing up. Check, check, and check. My immediate enthusiasm for the game may have been predictable, but the fact that I’m still playing it over 250 hours and 200 runs later? Not so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developer Supergiant Games released three games prior to &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;, and each one was an indie darling. The studio has racked up dozens, if not hundreds, of awards since their debut in 2011, and they’ve also been lauded for &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://kotaku.com/the-secret-to-the-success-of-bastion-pyre-and-hades-1838082618"&gt;&lt;span&gt;promoting a healthy work-life balance for their employees&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, something that’s not very common in the games industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/hades-lounge.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While Supergiant’s track record is one for the ages, &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; is their best game yet, an amalgamation of the best their previous titles have to offer — the narrative flair of &lt;em&gt;Bastion&lt;/em&gt;, the satisfying, punchy gameplay of &lt;em&gt;Transistor&lt;/em&gt;, and the genre-bending of &lt;em&gt;Pyre&lt;/em&gt;. Considering the title is fresh off some pretty huge wins at the BAFTAs, it seems like most people agree.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; really is a masterclass in excellent game design, and the easiest way to tell is that it’s fun all the way through. From the moment I picked up the controller, there wasn’t any point in the game I was wanting to rush through to get to the good stuff. You already have the core gameplay, which is so solid,  and you can really feel how much love and care went into it. On top of that, you have this colorful cast of characters coming to life, with their snappy dialogue and engaging storylines. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The most surprising additions to me, though, were the inclusions of the dating sim and decoration mechanics, something I certainly wasn’t expecting from a roguelike. What a great choice the developers made, because after finishing a run, feeling either frustrated or satisfied based on how it went, I would be so excited to check up on my friends or buy the new upgrade for the house I had been saving for. Every moment was delightful, and I love this game for it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/my-girl-artemis.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Speaking of the house, it’s not just a place to kick back and enjoy the Ambrosia — its effects on gameplay are what really makes &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; stand out as the perfect gateway roguelike. Rather than just dying and restarting as if your previous run never happened, you carry over any currencies you accrued during your run. Doing so allows you to power up and get stronger, meaning you’re going to get further on your next run and get more currency to come back and get stronger. That’s a pretty pristine gameplay loop if you ask me.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So the early game is awesome, and there’s nothing better than a game you can’t put down. But &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;‘s true addictive quality lies in its late game. There are a ton of different factors in play by the time you unlock everything — thirteen in total, if my math is correct. From the boons to the fishing mini game to the Erebus rooms, I could go on and on about how all of these different mechanics feed back into each other to create an airtight system, but there are only so many hours in the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Instead, let’s talk about the main mechanic that has me button mashing so hard my hands get sore and popping blood vessels in my eyes because I’m focusing so hard (true story): The Pact of Punishment. For those who may not know, the Pact allows you to add optional modifiers to make the game even harder than it already is, with rewards to be claimed if you can take it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So for example, you can choose to take more damage from enemies or have fewer options when power-ups are presented to you, stuff like that. Each individual modifier adds points to your “heat” total, and more difficult modifiers are worth more points. Simple enough.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/heat-meter.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Initially, I thought there was no way in hell, or in the underworld I guess, I was going to ever use that thing. Making the game more difficult, one modifier at a time? I could barely get through the Tartarus boss fight! But like the sweet song of a siren, it called to me. And after I got confident in beating Hades every time, I decided to give it a shot.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It was rough going at first. I was dying to enemies I could usually kill without even breaking a sweat. I was staying away from Chaos gates and praying for a fountain room so I could get some health back, which had become a precious resource by this point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/fountain-room.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Let me interrupt myself for an aside here, but I promise it’s important — something you should know about me is that I usually wasn’t someone who liked to challenge myself in a game to the point of frustration. I like stories, I like the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;feel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; of games, but I never dared venture above normal mode. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So, &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; initially kept me coming back for the narrative stuff, the look of it, and the UX that somehow scratches an itch in my brain (I can’t explain it, but the sound of the glass orb above a door shattering when you move on to the next room makes me feel things). But now, all I care about is the rush of narrowly defeating my fictional father at the highest heat my little hands can handle.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/hades-defeated.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I made my way up the heat meter, I could feel myself slowly but surely improving at the game. I was dodging into small gaps between enemy attacks, and going through multiple rooms without taking any damage at all. Instead of just taking whatever boons were given to me, I started forming longer-form strategies to min-max my build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It wasn’t all rainbows and unicorns though — around heat 14 I thought I had hit my skill ceiling. No matter which weapon or type of build I was running, it wasn’t working, and I was getting ready to throw in the towel for good. I couldn’t go for more than two runs at a time, because my fingers would get so sore.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;That was until I got one of my friends to start playing, and talking to him about it made me want to jump back in a few weeks later. I should’ve followed Supergiant’s lead sooner and let myself take a break because that’s what made a difference.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/theseus-fight.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I didn’t have to think, I was one with Zagreus, and Zagreus was one with me. &lt;/span&gt;I was in a flow state, all the time, and that’s a euphoric feeling. I went from feeling like I was chasing the win, stumbling along the way, to being out ahead of it, attacking it even. Maybe it’s just the Dionysus boons talking, but with each successive heat I beat, I felt drunk with power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I knew something really changed when I started button mashing through the dialogue. Who is this new Noelle? I don’t know, but I like her.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The point I’m trying to get at here is that &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span&gt; is an amazing game all around, but if you find yourself intimidated by titles like &lt;em&gt;Bloodborne&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Cuphead&lt;/em&gt;, it’s a great place to start. You’re having so much fun along the way, and the game eases you into its most challenging aspects so organically, you become a mechanically proficient player without even realizing it. For someone like me, that’s the ideal situation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/v1cdn.destructoid.com/lernie-fight.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;I always loved games, but &lt;em&gt;Hades&lt;/em&gt; helped me learn to love the challenge of them, and now I feel like I’ve fallen in love all over again. I’m now sitting around 20 heat, and it’s starting to get tough again, but now I know I can push through. I feel like I have something to prove, not to anyone else, but to myself. It’s an empowering feeling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;So I’m going for that 32 heat prize. I have no idea how long it’s going to take me to get there, but I’m not stopping until it’s mine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
Ares would be so proud
[Narrated by Josh Picard]
Hades was love at first sight for me. It has the bright and stylized art that I love, roguelikes are one of my favorite gameplay genres, and I was one of those Greek mythology kids who was obsessed with the Percy Jackson series growing up. Check, check, and check. My immediate enthusiasm for the game may have been predictable, but the fact that I’m still playing it over 250 hours and 200 runs later? Not so much.
Developer Supergiant Games released three games prior to Hades, and each one was an indie darling. The studio has racked up dozens, if not hundreds, of awards since their debut in 2011, and they’ve also been lauded for promoting a healthy work-life balance for their employees, something that’s not very common in the games industry.

While Supergiant’s track record is one for the ages, Hades is their best game yet, an amalgamation of the best their previous titles have to offer — the narrative flair of Bastion, the satisfying, punchy gameplay of Transistor, and the genre-bending of Pyre. Considering the title is fresh off some pretty huge wins at the BAFTAs, it seems like most people agree.
Hades really is a masterclass in excellent game design, and the easiest way to tell is that it’s fun all the way through. From the moment I picked up the controller, there wasn’t any point in the game I was wanting to rush through to get to the good stuff. You already have the core gameplay, which is so solid,  and you can really feel how much love and care went into it. On top of that, you have this colorful cast of characters coming to life, with their snappy dialogue and engaging storylines. 
The most surprising additions to me, though, were the inclusions of the dating sim and decoration mechanics, something I certainly wasn’t expecting from a roguelike. What a great choice the developers made, because after finishing a run, feeling either frustrated or satisfied based on how it went, I would be so excited to check up on my friends or buy the new upgrade for the house I had been saving for. Every moment was delightful, and I love this game for it.

Speaking of the house, it’s not just a place to kick back and enjoy the Ambrosia — its effects on gameplay are what really makes Hades stand out as the perfect gateway roguelike. Rather than just dying and restarting as if your previous run never happened, you carry over any currencies you accrued during your run. Doing so allows you to power up and get stronger, meaning you’re going to get further on your next run and get more currency to come back and get stronger. That’s a pretty pristine gameplay loop if you ask me.
So the early game is awesome, and there’s nothing better than a game you can’t put down. But Hades‘s true addictive quality lies in its late game. There are a ton of different factors in play by the time you unlock everything — thirteen in total, if my math is correct. From the boons to the fishing mini game to the Erebus rooms, I could go on and on about how all of these different mechanics feed back into each other to create an airtight system, but there are only so many hours in the day.
Instead, let’s talk about the main mechanic that has me button mashing so hard my hands get sore and popping blood vessels in my eyes because I’m focusing so hard (true story): The Pact of Punishment. For those who may not know, the Pact allows you to add optional modifiers to make the game even harder than it already is, with rewards to be claimed if you can take it. 
So for example, you can choose to take more damage from enemies or have fewer options when power-ups are presented to you, stuff like that. Each individual modifier adds points to your “heat” total, and more difficult modifiers are worth more points. Simple enough.

Initially, I thought there was no way in hell, or in the underworld I guess, I was going to ever use that thing. Making the game more difficult, one modifier at a time? I could barely get through the Tartarus boss fight! But like the sweet song of a siren, it called to me. And after I got confident in beating Hades every time, I decided to give it a shot.
It was rough going at first. I was dying to enemies I could usually kill without even breaking a sweat. I was staying away from Chaos gates and praying for a fountain room so I could get some health back, which had become a precious resource by this point.

Let me interrupt myself for an aside here, but I promise it’s important — something you should know about me is that I usually wasn’t someone who liked to challenge myself in a game to the point of frustration. I like stories, I like the feel of games, but I never dared venture above normal mode. 
So, Hades initially kept me coming back for the narrative stuff, the look of it, and the UX that somehow scratches an itch in my brain (I can’t explain it, but the sound of the glass orb above a door shattering when you move on to the next room makes me feel things). But now, all I care about is the rush of narrowly defeating my fictional father at the highest heat my little hands can handle.

As I made my way up the heat meter, I could feel myself slowly but surely improving at the game. I was dodging into small gaps between enemy attacks, and going through multiple rooms without taking any damage at all. Instead of just taking whatever boons were given to me, I started forming longer-form strategies to min-max my build.
It wasn’t all rainbows and unicorns though — around heat 14 I thought I had hit my skill ceiling. No matter which weapon or type of build I was running, it wasn’t working, and I was getting ready to throw in the towel for good. I couldn’t go for more than two runs at a time, because my fingers would get so sore.
That was until I got one of my friends to start playing, and talking to him about it made me want to jump back in a few weeks later. I should’ve followed Supergiant’s lead sooner and let myself take a break because that’s what made a difference.

I didn’t have to think, I was one with Zagreus, and Zagreus was one with me. I was in a flow state, all the time, and that’s a euphoric feeling. I went from feeling like I was chasing the win, stumbling along the way, to being out ahead of it, attacking it even. Maybe it’s just the Dionysus boons talking, but with each successive heat I beat, I felt drunk with power.
I knew something really changed when I started button mashing through the dialogue. Who is this new Noelle? I don’t know, but I like her.
The point I’m trying to get at here is that Hades is an amazing game all around, but if you find yourself intimidated by titles like Bloodborne or Cuphead, it’s a great place to start. You’re having so much fun along the way, and the game eases you into its most challenging aspects so organically, you become a mechanically proficient player without even realizing it. For someone like me, that’s the ideal situation.

I always loved games, but Hades helped me learn to love the challenge of them, and now I feel like I’ve fallen in love all over again. I’m now sitting around 20 heat, and it’s starting to get tough again, but now I know I can push through. I feel like I have something to prove, not to anyone else, but to myself. It’s an empowering feeling.
So I’m going for that 32 heat prize. I have no idea how long it’s going to take me to get there, but I’m not stopping until it’s mine.
</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/624522-styx-fight.jpg</image></item><item><title>Ninja Theory to donate $25K from Hellblade's Xbox One sales to Mental Health America</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/ninja-theory-to-donate-25k-from-hellblades-xbox-one-sales-to-mental-health-america/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T06:29:11+00:00</created_at><description>50,000 units sold on Microsoft format This month saw the release of the BAFTA award-winning Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice on Xbox One. After shifting over 50,000 units in first few weeks, developers Ninja...</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;50,000 units sold on Microsoft format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month saw the release of the BAFTA award-winning &lt;em&gt;Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice&lt;/em&gt; on Xbox One. After shifting over 50,000 units in first few weeks, developers Ninja Theory are to donate thousands of dollars to the Mental Health America organisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sombre adventure title, which launched last year on PS4 and PC, stars a young warrior woman who embarks on a nightmarish journey to save the soul of her lover, battle otherworldly monstrosities and the crippling anguish within her own mind, a psychosis which she believes to be a curse. The game was lauded for its sensitive treatment of mental illness, attained through the developers working alongside neurosurgeons and those who are affected themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the first time Ninja Theory have donated money from &lt;em&gt;Hellblade&lt;/em&gt; sales to mental health charities. On World Mental Health Day 2017, the &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/all-proceeds-from-hellblade-sales-today-will-be-donated-to-uk-mental-health-charity-466234.phtml" target="_blank"&gt;proceeds from all sales of the game&lt;/a&gt; within a 24-hour period were given to UK charity Rethink; an organisation I myself have required the aid of many times. Ninja Theory have stated that although they didn’t reach their intended goal of 100,000 units, they will donate a further $50K whenever they hit that milestone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said it then, and I’ll repeat myself now; I sincerely hope that any members of our beloved community, who are affected by such issues, be it they themselves, or their loved ones, can find comfort, support and relief through friends, family, colleagues, forums and healthcare professionals. You are not alone in this, nor do you ever have to be, I promise you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice&lt;/em&gt; is available now on PS4, Xbox One and PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Hellblade?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#Hellblade&lt;/a&gt; hit over 50K Week 1 sales on &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/XboxOne?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#XboxOne&lt;/a&gt;! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all your support!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now donate $25K to Mental Health America! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although we didn’t reach our stretch goal of 100K units to donate $50K, we have decided to still donate the full $50K when we do hit 100K sales! &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://t.co/fPts8WukAs"&gt;pic.twitter.com/fPts8WukAs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— NinjaTheory (@NinjaTheory) &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/NinjaTheory/status/987012590952992769?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;April 19, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/av-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/av-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Senior Editor - Chris has been playing video games since the 1980s. Former Saturday Night Slam Master. Graduated from Galaxy High with honors. Twitter: @ChrisxMoyse&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
50,000 units sold on Microsoft format
This month saw the release of the BAFTA award-winning Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice on Xbox One. After shifting over 50,000 units in first few weeks, developers Ninja Theory are to donate thousands of dollars to the Mental Health America organisation.
The sombre adventure title, which launched last year on PS4 and PC, stars a young warrior woman who embarks on a nightmarish journey to save the soul of her lover, battle otherworldly monstrosities and the crippling anguish within her own mind, a psychosis which she believes to be a curse. The game was lauded for its sensitive treatment of mental illness, attained through the developers working alongside neurosurgeons and those who are affected themselves.
This isn’t the first time Ninja Theory have donated money from Hellblade sales to mental health charities. On World Mental Health Day 2017, the proceeds from all sales of the game within a 24-hour period were given to UK charity Rethink; an organisation I myself have required the aid of many times. Ninja Theory have stated that although they didn’t reach their intended goal of 100,000 units, they will donate a further $50K whenever they hit that milestone.
I said it then, and I’ll repeat myself now; I sincerely hope that any members of our beloved community, who are affected by such issues, be it they themselves, or their loved ones, can find comfort, support and relief through friends, family, colleagues, forums and healthcare professionals. You are not alone in this, nor do you ever have to be, I promise you.
Hellblade: Senua’s Sacrifice is available now on PS4, Xbox One and PC.

#Hellblade hit over 50K Week 1 sales on #XboxOne! 
Thanks for all your support!
We can now donate $25K to Mental Health America! 
Although we didn’t reach our stretch goal of 100K units to donate $50K, we have decided to still donate the full $50K when we do hit 100K sales! pic.twitter.com/fPts8WukAs
— NinjaTheory (@NinjaTheory) April 19, 2018

 

Senior Editor - Chris has been playing video games since the 1980s. Former Saturday Night Slam Master. Graduated from Galaxy High with honors. Twitter: @ChrisxMoyse



</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/499700-hllls.jpg</image></item><item><title>Rocket League going free to play next week, will be delisted from Steam</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/rocket-league-going-free-to-play-next-week-will-be-delisted-from-steam/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T06:22:28+00:00</created_at><description>‘What a save’ for everyone Back in July, Psyonix announced that its wildly popular socc-car game Rocket League would be going free-to-play. At the time there was only a vague “in the future” release window....</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;‘What a save’ for everyone&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in July, Psyonix announced that its wildly popular socc-car game &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; would be going &lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/stories/rocket-league-is-going-free-to-play-getting-cross-platform-account-merging-598089.phtml" target="_blank"&gt;free-to-play&lt;/a&gt;. At the time there was only a vague “in the future” release window. Today, Psyonix announced on Twitter that the go-live date for the free-to-play changeover would be September 23.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the week leading up to the F2P launch, there will be an update that will officially change all active accounts over to legacy status that will bring with it multiple benefits. The most tantalizing perk will be the gift of all previously released &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; branded DLCs as thanks for being an “early” adopter. The full details of what legacy status will entail can be found on the &lt;a href="https://www.rocketleague.com/news/rocket-league-going-free-to-play-this-summer/" target="_blank"&gt;official site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, users can begin merging their accounts through an Epic Games account. There’s also going to be an event called Llama-Rama to celebrate the F2P launch, but details, for now, are being held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As expected, this move to F2P will also spell the end of &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; being listed on the Steam storefront. Steam users will still be able to launch the game through Steam but starting tomorrow, no new PC users will be allowed to download the game outside of the Epic Games Store. The update will go live tomorrow morning so if you’re continuing to avoid the Epic Games launcher then you have only a scant few hours to get it on Steam before the listing is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we go from here, no one knows. It has been a long road that led to this and while I have my problems with some of the more toxic bastions of the community, I still love &lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; with all of my heart. It will be interesting to see how the meta evolves in the F2P era and how many of us old geezers will be left in the dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rocket League&lt;/em&gt; is available on PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, and starting tomorrow exclusively through the Epic Games Store on PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.rocketleague.com/news/rocket-league-free-to-play-arrives-september-23/"&gt;Rocket League going Free to Play September 23&lt;/a&gt; [Psyonix]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/EmmyIcon-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/EmmyIcon-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Contributor for Dtoid and news editor of Flixist. Lover of all things strategic and independent.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>
‘What a save’ for everyone
Back in July, Psyonix announced that its wildly popular socc-car game Rocket League would be going free-to-play. At the time there was only a vague “in the future” release window. Today, Psyonix announced on Twitter that the go-live date for the free-to-play changeover would be September 23.

In the week leading up to the F2P launch, there will be an update that will officially change all active accounts over to legacy status that will bring with it multiple benefits. The most tantalizing perk will be the gift of all previously released Rocket League branded DLCs as thanks for being an “early” adopter. The full details of what legacy status will entail can be found on the official site.
This week, users can begin merging their accounts through an Epic Games account. There’s also going to be an event called Llama-Rama to celebrate the F2P launch, but details, for now, are being held.
As expected, this move to F2P will also spell the end of Rocket League being listed on the Steam storefront. Steam users will still be able to launch the game through Steam but starting tomorrow, no new PC users will be allowed to download the game outside of the Epic Games Store. The update will go live tomorrow morning so if you’re continuing to avoid the Epic Games launcher then you have only a scant few hours to get it on Steam before the listing is gone.
Where we go from here, no one knows. It has been a long road that led to this and while I have my problems with some of the more toxic bastions of the community, I still love Rocket League with all of my heart. It will be interesting to see how the meta evolves in the F2P era and how many of us old geezers will be left in the dust.
Rocket League is available on PlayStation 4, Xbox One, Nintendo Switch, and starting tomorrow exclusively through the Epic Games Store on PC.
Rocket League going Free to Play September 23 [Psyonix]

 

Contributor for Dtoid and news editor of Flixist. Lover of all things strategic and independent.



</textplain><image>https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/603590-RL-F2P-cover.jpg</image></item><item><title>Immortal Redneck, a wacky roguelite FPS, is free-to-keep on GOG</title><link>https://www.destructoid.com/immortal-redneck-free-gog-deal-old-school-arcade-fps-roguelite-game/</link><created_at>2022-11-03T06:28:10+00:00</created_at><description>September 5 is the deadline Immortal Redneck might not ring a bell, but it’s free on PC, and it’s worth checking out. You’ve got until 6:00 a.m. Pacific on Monday, September 5 to add it to your GOG library....</description><content>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Immortal-Redneck-mummy-screenshot.jpg" alt="Immortal Redneck free" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;September 5 is the deadline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Immortal Redneck&lt;/em&gt; might not ring a bell, but it’s &lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/#giveaway" target="_blank"&gt;free on PC&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s worth checking out. You’ve got until 6:00 a.m. Pacific on Monday, &lt;strong&gt;September 5&lt;/strong&gt; to add it to your GOG library. There’s a “claim” button on GOG’s front page, and you’ll need to sign into your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VGyvt1Vk5bs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an ancient-Egypt-themed FPS that’s aiming for the old-school, fast-paced &lt;em&gt;Doom&lt;/em&gt; crowd while also working in a modern roguelite progression system like &lt;em&gt;Rogue Legacy&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect mythological shootouts in pyramids, plenty of verticality in the level design, a buuunch of weapons, big bosses, unlockable alternate starting classes, and an unavoidable stat-boosting grind as you upgrade your skill tree from run to run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways, I feel like &lt;em&gt;Immortal Redneck&lt;/em&gt; is speaking to two very different (and in some cases incompatible) crowds, but with so many “standard” throwback shooters popping up these days, the run-based structure helps it stand out. Above all, it feels good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://i0.wp.com/d220lhlugu3kfc.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Immortal-Redneck-skill-tree-screenshot.jpg?resize=640%2C360&amp;amp;ssl=1" alt="Immortal Redneck skill tree" /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Gold is a crucial part of the progression loop.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arena shooter flair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-immortal-redneck/" target="_blank"&gt;In his 2017 review&lt;/a&gt;, Chris Carter was pretty high on &lt;em&gt;Immortal Redneck&lt;/em&gt;, in large part due to its shooter fundamentals. The key quote: “While many studios have attempted to recreate the magic of the original &lt;em&gt;Unreal Tournament&lt;/em&gt; or the arena shooters of old and failed, developer Crema managed to get it right. […] While the roguelike setup will no doubt scare some people off (you do you, reader), anyone looking to temporarily transport themselves back through the ages of FPS-dom without making concessions should give it a chance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not necessarily a game you’ll want to fully finish — less-than-friendly roguelite tuning is one of the issues — but for free, &lt;em&gt;Immortal Redneck&lt;/em&gt; is an easy game to dabble in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GOG is also hosting a sale right now, hence this foot-in-the-door giveaway. Games like &lt;em&gt;Deux Ex GOTY Edition&lt;/em&gt; ($0.97), &lt;em&gt;Tomb Raider: Anniversary&lt;/em&gt; ($0.98), and &lt;em&gt;Heroes of Might and Magic 3: Complete&lt;/em&gt; ($2.49) are &lt;a href="https://www.gog.com/en/games" target="_blank"&gt;charting as best-sellers&lt;/a&gt;. A few bucks can take you far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jordan-Devore-avatar-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Jordan-Devore-avatar.jpg 2x" /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Jordan is a founding member of Destructoid and poster of seemingly random pictures. They are anything but random.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;article&gt;
			&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/Zelda.jpg" alt="Zelda: Breath of the Wild" /&gt;			&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;div&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;My asterisk is probably common&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.destructoid.com/reviews/review-the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has given tons of people hundreds hours of stuff to do, but is there anything on your list you haven’t checked off yet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question was spurred on &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Breath_of_the_Wild/comments/y8t8zp/almost_fell_out_of_my_chair_upon_seeing_this/"&gt;by this reddit post by Wickerchair&lt;/a&gt;, who mused on playing “400+ hours” of &lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; coming across a “???” unidentified item. Another really interesting story comes from Grancola1920, who mentioned in the comments that they “recently ran into a bug with ‘???’ after 700+ hours and it flew away before [they] could catch it. Now [they’re] on a Hyrule wide bug hunt.” It’s amazing that stories like these can still come out of this game, even if a lot of folks have moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about the missed connections, or abandoned quests?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For me, it’s the &lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; Korok Seeds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know! I 100%ed the game otherwise (all items that I know of/shrines): everything except the Korok Seeds. I was going to do it (and made good progress before guides were invented!), &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://zelda.fandom.com/wiki/Korok_Seed#:~:text=In%20exchange%20for%20Korok%20Seeds,a%20%22gift%20of%20friendship.%22"&gt;but once I saw the reward&lt;/a&gt;, I just couldn’t go through with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I always had a certain degree of satisfaction 100%ing games. Not every game was “worthy” of it, in that sense, but the ones I really connected to, I did go for it. But the real cherry on top of that sometimes grueling walk to that sundae was the reward. In character action games, it was occasionally a new costume or some insane toggle that fundamentally transformed the game in some way. That’s enough for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But 900 &lt;em&gt;Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/em&gt; Korok Seeds with no real reward? That’s where I check out!&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;div&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt src="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-96x96.jpg" srcset="https://www.destructoid.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/10/ChrisCarterAvatar-2-192x192.jpg 2x" /&gt;				&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;div&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chris Carter&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!&lt;/span&gt;
					&lt;/p&gt;
				&lt;/div&gt;
			&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><textplain>


 

September 5 is the deadline
Immortal Redneck might not ring a bell, but it’s free on PC, and it’s worth checking out. You’ve got until 6:00 a.m. Pacific on Monday, September 5 to add it to your GOG library. There’s a “claim” button on GOG’s front page, and you’ll need to sign into your account.

This is an ancient-Egypt-themed FPS that’s aiming for the old-school, fast-paced Doom crowd while also working in a modern roguelite progression system like Rogue Legacy.
Expect mythological shootouts in pyramids, plenty of verticality in the level design, a buuunch of weapons, big bosses, unlockable alternate starting classes, and an unavoidable stat-boosting grind as you upgrade your skill tree from run to run.
In some ways, I feel like Immortal Redneck is speaking to two very different (and in some cases incompatible) crowds, but with so many “standard” throwback shooters popping up these days, the run-based structure helps it stand out. Above all, it feels good.
Gold is a crucial part of the progression loop.
Arena shooter flair
In his 2017 review, Chris Carter was pretty high on Immortal Redneck, in large part due to its shooter fundamentals. The key quote: “While many studios have attempted to recreate the magic of the original Unreal Tournament or the arena shooters of old and failed, developer Crema managed to get it right. […] While the roguelike setup will no doubt scare some people off (you do you, reader), anyone looking to temporarily transport themselves back through the ages of FPS-dom without making concessions should give it a chance.”
It’s not necessarily a game you’ll want to fully finish — less-than-friendly roguelite tuning is one of the issues — but for free, Immortal Redneck is an easy game to dabble in.
GOG is also hosting a sale right now, hence this foot-in-the-door giveaway. Games like Deux Ex GOTY Edition ($0.97), Tomb Raider: Anniversary ($0.98), and Heroes of Might and Magic 3: Complete ($2.49) are charting as best-sellers. A few bucks can take you far.

 

Jordan is a founding member of Destructoid and poster of seemingly random pictures. They are anything but random.





 


						
	
		My asterisk is probably common
Zelda: Breath of the Wild has given tons of people hundreds hours of stuff to do, but is there anything on your list you haven’t checked off yet?
This question was spurred on by this reddit post by Wickerchair, who mused on playing “400+ hours” of Zelda: Breath of the Wild, and still coming across a “???” unidentified item. Another really interesting story comes from Grancola1920, who mentioned in the comments that they “recently ran into a bug with ‘???’ after 700+ hours and it flew away before [they] could catch it. Now [they’re] on a Hyrule wide bug hunt.” It’s amazing that stories like these can still come out of this game, even if a lot of folks have moved on.
But what about the missed connections, or abandoned quests?
For me, it’s the Zelda: Breath of the Wild Korok Seeds
I know! I 100%ed the game otherwise (all items that I know of/shrines): everything except the Korok Seeds. I was going to do it (and made good progress before guides were invented!), but once I saw the reward, I just couldn’t go through with it.
Growing up, I always had a certain degree of satisfaction 100%ing games. Not every game was “worthy” of it, in that sense, but the ones I really connected to, I did go for it. But the real cherry on top of that sometimes grueling walk to that sundae was the reward. In character action games, it was occasionally a new costume or some insane toggle that fundamentally transformed the game in some way. That’s enough for me.
But 900 Zelda: Breath of the Wild Korok Seeds with no real reward? That’s where I check out!
		
								
				
					Chris Carter
					
					Reviews Director, Co-EIC - Chris has been enjoying Destructoid avidly since 2008. He finally decided to take the next step, make an account, and start blogging in January of 2009. Now, he's staff!
					
				
			
	

 
</textplain><image>https://d23gn3985hkc32.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/Immortal-Redneck-mummy-screenshot.jpg</image></item></items></response>
